Register of the Milly Bennett papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Milly Bennett papers
1915-1960
82073
Hoover Institution Archives
21 manuscript boxes, 1 album box, 24 envelopes (12.5 linear feet)
Memoirs, news dispatches, other writings, correspondence, clippings, and photographs relating to political conditions in China, social conditions in the Soviet Union, the Spanish Civil War, and journalism in the United States.
Bennett, Milly, 1897-1960.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982, with incremental materials received at a later date.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1897 May 22 Born, San Francisco, California
1915 Graduate, Girls High School, San Francisco
1915-1917 Attended University of Hawaii
1917-1921 Reporter, The Daily News, San Francisco
1921 Married Mike Mitchell
1921-1926 Reporter, The Honolulu Star-Bulletin, Honolulu, Hawaii
1926 Divorced from Mike Mitchell
1926-1927 Editor, Chung-Mei News Agency, Peking, China Assistant Editor, Peoples Tribune, Hankow, China
1927-1931 Reporter, The Daily News, San Francisco; Scripps-Howard News Service; United Press; Newspaper Enterprise Association
circa 1931 Married Evgeni Konstantinov, Moscow, U.S.S.R.
1931-1935 Reporter, Moscow Daily News
1931-1936 Resident, U.S.S.R.
1935-1936 Reporter, Newspaper Enterprise Association; The New York Times; International News Service
1936-1937 Reporter from Spain for Associated Press, United Press, London Times Staff member, English-language section, Press and Propaganda Service, Foreign Ministry, Spanish Popular Front Government
1937 Married Hans Amlie
1938 Returned to the United States
1960 Died
Milly Bennett was the pseudonym of Mildred Jacqueline Bremler, who also wrote under her married names, Mildred Mitchell and Mildred Amlie.
Scope and Content of Collection
Memoirs, news dispatches, other writings, correspondence, clippings, and photographs relating to political conditions in China, social conditions in the Soviet Union, the Spanish Civil War, and journalism in the United States.
Journalism--United States.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; Spain--History--Civil War, 1936-1939.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.; Journalists.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1919-1942 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Memorabilia, newspaper articles, souvenirs belonging to Milly Bennett and her three husbands, Mike Mitchell, Evgeni Konstantinov, and Hans Amlie, arranged chronologically.
  - General (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - High school diploma and yearbook (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Magazine article, "Heroes of Labor," Time, quoting Milly Bennett, 1935 December 16 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Membership cards, ads for speeches, press passes, identity cards (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Newspaper articles about Milly Bennett
    - 1919 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Marriage of Milly Bennett and Mike Mitchell, circa 1921 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Arrest in China, 1927 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Experiences in China, 1928 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - Writing career, 1929 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - Experiences in the Soviet Union, 1932 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Milly Bennett's interview with Alfred Lunt and Lynn Fontaine, 1933 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - Izvestia and Pravda articles, 1936 November (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Milly Bennett and Hans Amlie in Spain and their marriage, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Speaking engagements, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - O.G.P.U. - document on arrest of Milly Bennett's second husband, Evgeni Konstantinov, 1934 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Outline of Milly Bennett's career (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Safe conduct passes for Milly Bennett in Spain (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Souvenirs belonging to Hans Amlie (Box-folder 1: 18)
    Includes calling cards, Spanish money, and safe conduct passes.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1926-1956 (Boxes 1-5)
  Arrangement Statement
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Unidentified
    - Undated (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - 1927-1928 (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - 1930-1933 (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - 1930-1933 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1934 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - 1935 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - 1936-1940 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - 1941-1944 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Abramson, S. H., 1937 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Allan, Bill and Seema, circa 1934 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Allen, Robert S., 1938 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Amlie, Hans, 1938-1944 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Amlie, Paul J., 1938-1944 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Arthur, Chester A., 1942 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Baillie, Constance, undated (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Ballantine, Betty, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Barnes, Esther, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Benet, Frances Rose, 1937 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1939 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Bremler, Mrs. (mother of Milly Bennett), 1926 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Bridges, Billie, undated (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Buckley, Edmund, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Bullitt, William C., 1940 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Burkhards, William, circa 1930 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Burnett, James, Sir, undated (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Burton, Wallace, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Burton, Wilbur (?), 1926-1927 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - California State Board of Prison Directors, 1929 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - California State Relief Administration, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - Copeland, A. R., Mrs., 1943 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Cornwell, Warren, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1939 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Dalyrymple, Martha, undated (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Detro, Agnes, 1938-1943 (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - Dodd, Martha (?), 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - Dooling, Mary, undated (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - Douning, Myrtle, 1948 (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - Edmundson, Charles, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 35)
  - French, Lucille, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 2: 36)
  - Friends of Democracy, Inc., 1944 (Box-folder 2: 37)
  - Fuqua, Stephen O., 1940-1942 (Box-folder 2: 38)
  - Garoffolo, Vincent, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 39)
  - Givens, Alice, undated (Box-folder 2: 40)
  - Goodall, Donald, 1939 (Box-folder 2: 41)
  - Gould, Grace, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2: 42)
  - Gould, Randall, 1940, undated (Box-folder 2: 43)
  - Greene, Abel, 1937 (Box-folder 2: 44)
  - Hall, L., undated (Box-folder 2: 45)
  - Hampel, "Sis,", 1938-1942 (Box-folder 2: 46)
  - Hawkins, Maurice, 1938 (Box-folder 2: 47)
  - Herbst, Jo, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 48)
  - Hoover Library, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 2: 49)
  - International Labor Defense, 1931 (Box-folder 2: 50)
  - International News Service, 1936 (Box-folder 2: 51)
  - James, Bessie L., 1938 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - James, Edwin L., 1940 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Jones, George S., 1943 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Jones, R. M., undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Klutts, Henry and Dot, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Knoblaugh, Ed, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Konstantinov, Evgeni Vasilivich (Zhenya)
    - Undated (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - 1934 (Box-folder 3: 10-13)
    - 1935 (Box-folder 3: 14-15)
  - Logan, Milla, circa 1942 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Magdiel, Daniel and Valborg, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Mangan, Kate, undated (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Mann, Tom (?), undated (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Manson, Dan, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Marca, Arnold, undated (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Matson, Harold, 1938-1943 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - McCann, Steve and Tinka, 1956 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - McKillop, Marjorie, 1938-1944 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Merrick, Owen, undated (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Miller, Bob and Jenny, 1937-1944 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Montrose, Sherman and Ethel, 1945 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Morris, Gerry, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Muggeridge, Eric, 1939 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Muller, Hermann, 1937 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Murphy, circa 1938 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - National League of American Pen Women, 1939 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Ness, Roy, 1942 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Norris, Charles and K., undated (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1937 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - O'Connor, Jim, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Offie, 1937 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Olson, Culbert, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Parker, Dorothy, 1937 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Phillips, Joseph B., 1942 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Podesta, Evelyn Wells, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Prohme, Rayna, 1927 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Prohme, William, 1934 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Radomsky, Sergei (?), 1937 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Raffel, Daniel and Rosalee, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Roessner, Elmer, 1934-1937 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Rose, Sol, 1937 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - Ross, C. Blake, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 4: 24-25)
  - Rothman, Kajsa, 1937-1943 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - San Francisco-Oakland Newspaper Guild, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Sartain, Geraldine, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Seldes, George and Helen, 1938, undated (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Shaver, J. J., Mrs. (sister of Wallace and Wilbur Burton), 1937 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Sheean, Vincent, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Shirer, William, 1941 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Smith, Charles, 1931, undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Steward, Pearl, 1939 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Strong, Anna Louise, 1931-1944 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Sutro, Ralph C., Mrs., 1941 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Van Ansdal, Alvin, undated (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Vanderburgh, W. W. and Rose, Drs., 1939 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Vaughn, Peg, 1936 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Wachtel, Marion, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Wiley, Donald and Marjorie, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Williams, Beryl, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Williams, Spencer, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Wilson, J. E. and Mary Ann, 1939-1944 (Box-folder 5: 19)
- COLLECTED CORRESPONDENCE, 1927-1944 (Box 5)
  Arranged alphabetically by writer of correspondence.
  - Amlie, Hans (correspondence to and from Hans Amlie, third husband of Milly Bennett), 1937-1944 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Amlie, Thomas, to Hans Amlie, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Besant, G. A., Jr., to all Austinites, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Douglass, Leon F., to W. N. Burkhards, 1929 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Fox, Charles James, to Randall Gould, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Gould, Randall, to Rayna Prohme, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Houser, Lionel, to Elmer Roessner, 1936 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Prohme, William, to Dr. Kou Meng-yu, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Sun Yat-sen, Mme, to Rayna Prohme, circa 1927 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Wintringham, T. H., to Robert Minor, 1937 (Box-folder 5: 29)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1917-circa 1956 (Boxes 6-14)
  Newspaper articles, drafts, magazine articles, book manuscripts, and research materials in holograph, typescript, carbon copies, and processed form, arranged chronologically, alphabetically, and in order of appearance (series).
  - Holograph notes, undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings (many with Milly Bennett's by-line), 1917-1921 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Verses, 1917-1926 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Articles and manuscripts
    - "Ah, Girls, Have You See Wilson's Doctor,", undated (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - "Birthday Is Celebrated On Way to Prison,", undated
    - "Child Faces Anthony With Her Story,", undated
    - "Daily News Reporter Sits in Court of Woman Judge,", undated
    - "Guns on Casco Hold Up Treasure Hunt,", undated
    - "'I'm Very Well, Dear' Mrs. Wilson Tells Reporter,", undated
    - "Orphans Shiver While Clothes Are Rushed to Burned Home,", undated
    - "Reporter Sits on Pier in Early Morn; 'Rescued' Four Times,", undated
    - "San Quentin Visit Gives S.F. Judge New Crime Philosophy,", undated
    - "Starvation Pay Is Cause of Rail Strike, Men Say,", undated
    - "'Wild Westers' Arrive on Oakland Side in Night,", undated
    - "Wilson's Envoy in City: Saw Kaiser in 1915,", undated
    - "Writer Brands Probe of Russ a Farce,", undated
    - "Milly Bennett, Maid" series, 1917 February (Box-folder 6: 5)
      In the sequence in which they appeared. Number nine is missing and the headline in number seventeen is illegible.
      - "'Milly Bennett' Gets First Job in City Home"
      - "'Milly' Quits; Seeks Work in Big Hotel"
      - "'Milly' Tries New Agency; Is Recognized"
      - "Jobless, 'Milly' Haunts Employment Bureaus"
      - "'Milly Bennett' Clashes With Stranger; Seeks Army Job"
      - "'Milly' Gets Job as Second Maid"
      - "'Milly' Quits After Day of Housework"
      - "'Milly' on New Job Overturns Bowl of Soup"
      - "'Milly' Finds Silent Service Is Difficult"
      - "'Milly' Invited to Party, Goes Through Ordeal"
      - "'Milly' Leaves Country Job; Returns Home"
      - "Send 'Milly' to Home of Acquaintance"
      - "'Milly' Almost Gets Job in Big Home"
      - "'Milly' in Berkeley Home Rebels at Cap"
      - "'Milly' Learns Proper Way to Tend Door"
      - "Beaus Are Bars to Job, 'Milly' Finds"
      - "'Milly' Goes to Work for Police Judge"
      - "'Milly Bennett' Ends Her Career as Maid"
    - "Hundreds Stranded in Berry Districts,", 1917 June (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - "Won't Send Boys to Farms, Say Officials,", 1917 June
    - "'Mother' Jones Comes to Help 'Her Boy',", 1918 April (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Series on the California Women's Army entitled "A Soldier of the Sod,", 1918 June (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - "'Newsboy Row' Desolate; 'Mother Lillian' Stricken,", 1918 November (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - "Civilized Life Palls; Pair Seek Solitude,", 1919 April (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - "Held Under 'Spell' Says S.F. Woman,", 1919 April
    - Series entitled "Oneita of the Ozarks,", 1919 May-June (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - "Boy, 9, Penniless, Lives Two Weeks in City,", 1919 June (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - "Daughters of Syrian Banker 'Bus-Girls' Now,", 1919 June
    - "Fund Completed Rocca Boy Gets a New Leg,", 1919 June
    - "Girl Confesses Love for Herbert Law,", 1919 June
    - "Grant-av,", 1919 June
    - "Northcott Pose Gone; Nerve Slips, Reporter Finds,", 1919 June
    - "Raid,", 1919 June
    - "Every One But Santa to Be Cheered Today,", 1919 August (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - "Find S.F. Meeting Place for 300 of Bolsheviki,", 1919 August
    - "Hard Luck,", 1919 August
    - "If 'Wheezer' Could Pitch With His Nose,", 1919 August
    - "Irish of America Will Aid Revolt, Says Kathleen O'Brennan,", 1919 August
    - "Jail Is Better Than Home, Thinks Carmelo Garcia,", 1919 August
    - "Oakland Judge Turns Hobo to Study Men,", 1919 August
    - "Thurston Says Wife Should Have Killed Him and Not Miss Kimball,", 1919 August
    - "Destitute Squatters Near Panic Stage as Government Prepares to Evict Them,", 1919 September
    - "New Reds Will Uphold the Glory of Old Reds - McVey,", 1919 September
    - "Woman Leads Move for Federal Service Shop Steward Plan,", 1919 September
    - "Woman Wanted Clothes, Drugs; Robbed for Them,", 1919 September
    - "Yep! S.F. Sure Wanted to See the Fleet,", 1919 September
    - Series on American Forces in Siberia, 1919 September-October (Box-folder 6: 14)
      - "Americans Used to Break Mine Strike in Siberia, Says Veteran"
      - "Canadian Veteran Declares He Robbed Drunken Officers Charity"
      - "Crime for U.S. to Send 'Kids' to Siberia, Claim"
      - "Destitute Squatters Near Panic Stage as Government Prepares to Evict Them"
      - "Finds Siberia-Bound Lads Want 'To See World'"
      - "He'd Drink Before He Would Return to Siberian Service"
      - "Kopec Hill and Vodka Yanks' Only Relief in Vladivostok"
      - "Manacles Welded on Yanks, Says Veteran"
      - "Morale Is Gone, Says Siberian Soldier, Just Returned"
      - "More Men of 27th, 31st home From Siberia"
      - "Mother Walker Waits in Vain for Soldier Son"
      - "Returned Yanks Tell of 'War' in Russia"
      - "Siberian Veterans Tell Bitter Stories"
      - "Soldiers Don't Know Why They Went to Siberia"
      - "13 Trials, 1 Suicide in Month in Siberia Company"
      - "U.S. Officers in Siberia Often Drunk, He Says"
      - "Veterans Are Afraid to Talk"
      - "Vodka Drives American Soldiers Mad, Siberian Veteran Declares"
      - "'Why Are Yanks in Siberia?' Veterans Ask"
      - "Yanks in Siberia For Private Interests"
      - "Yanks in Siberia Study Maps to Find Ways to Make Their Escape"
    - "Couldn't Stand Sight of Slain Husband, Says Slayer in Prison", 1919 November (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - "Home Town Paper Vendors See Life Pass on S.F. Streets,", 1919 November
    - "Jury Duty Proves Strenuous to 'Society',", 1919 November
    - "Lou Eagan Gets Real Fund From Theaters,", 1919 November
    - "Verdi, World Rover, Wants To Stay in Petlama (sic),", 1919 November
    - "'Waterfront Widow' Hit by Dry Laws,", 1919 November
    - "Women Gossip at 'Flirt Murder' Trial,", 1919 November
    - "You Can't Cure a Drug Victim, Declares Jim M'Quaide,", 1919 November
    - Series on Travelers Aid Society of San Francisco, 1920 March (Box-folder 6: 16)
      In sequence in which they appeared.
      - "'Husband' Is a Myth; Girl Tells Tragic Tale"
      - "Girl Victim of War Works In S.F. Millinery Shop"
      - "Girl Comes to S.F. For Joy, Finds Tragedy Waiting"
      - "Weeks of Toil Do Not Bring Sweetheart"
      - "Finnish Strangers Lost in Strange Maze of S.F."
      - "Girl's Tragedy Turns Into Happiness"
      - "Vice Rings Foiled by 'Badge' Women"
    - "'Fate Made Me a Murderess,' Says Woman,", 1921 September (Box-folder 6: 17)
    - Series, 1922 March
      - "Girl Reporter, With Only $5, Starts to Find Job in S.F." (Box-folder 6: 18)
      - "Girl Hunting Job, Applies to S.F. Salvation Army for Aid"
      - "Girl Reporter Finds Job First Day She Goes on Her Hunt"
      - "Milly Bennett Gets Acquainted With Girls Working in Factory"
    - Series, 1922 August
      - "Crawling Like a Dirty Bug in Heavy Dust -- That Is Weed"
      - "Men Held Like Slaves in Lumber Camps"
      - "Lumber Company Owns Towns, Keeps Peace Officials on Its Payroll"
    - "Destitute Squatters Near Panic Stage as Government Prepares to Evict Them,", 1923 (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - "A Few Words by Milly,", 1923
    - "The Kona Coast: A Place to Dream,", 1923
    - "The Kona Coast - Arcadia - A Place to Rest and Dream,", 1923
    - "Memories of Honolulu,", 1923
    - "On the Kona Coast,", 1923
    - "She Walked in Beauty and Found the True Feeling That Is Hawaii,", 1923
    - "When the Old Burg Went Mad,", 1923
    - "Girl Griffin, Piloted by Gay Young Blade, Fails to Find Lovely Russian in Native City,", 1926 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - "Orient Is Not So Dangerous,", 1926
    - "Sun Has Set in Far East For Foreigners: 'China For Chinese' Is Battle Cry,", 1926
    - "'Teapot Dome' Shattered by U.S. Gun Fire,", 1926
    - Letter to the Editor of the Peking and Tientsin Times, 1927 April (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - Series in The San Francisco News, 1927 November (Box-folder 7: 3)
      - "'Butterflying' Into China's Revolt"
      - "Flames Save Milly's Life; Red Secrets Burned as Peking Police Storm at Her Door"
      - "Hope for United China Lies in Education and Industry"
      - "Talking to the $100,000 Head"
    - Series entitled "Palmy Days" by E. J. Quillinan as told to Milly Bennett, 1928 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - "Flaming Youth Old Style, Novelist Says,", 1929 March (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - "Failure? Man in Almshouse Is Triumphant,", 1929 May
    - "He Failed, But World Fails, Too, His Solace,", 1929 May
    - "Life's a 'Lulu' Relief Home Inmate Finds,", 1929 May
    - "Meekness Is One Road to a Poorhouse,", 1929 May
    - "Blue Blood, No Less, Flows in S.F. Poorhouse,", 1929 June
    - "Charity Plea in Newspaper 'Racket' Hit,", 1929 June
    - "Fast Horses Convey Him 'Over the Hill',", 1929 June
    - "She Tumbles From Trapeze to Poorhouse,", 1929 June
    - "Stanford to the Ganges,", 1929 June
    - Trip to Central America, Venezuela, Mexico, Cuba and Colombia, 1929 August-September (Box-folder 7: 6)
      Carbon copy of article on the trip, answers to questions (in Spanish) presented to the President of Guatemala by Milly Bennett, copy of The Voice of the Passengers edited by Milly Bennett on board the S.S. Colombia.
    - "Janitor's Big Moment Comes at Court Session,", circa 1930 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - "Love in a Fudge Box,", circa 1930
    - "Mrs. Mooney Keeps Up High Heart for Son,", circa 1930
    - "Old West Still Lives in Lively Border Town,", circa 1930
    - "A Scripps Slave Spends a Profitable Morn Over Her Keys" (carbon), circa 1930
    - "Vets Protest Ban on Radios at Livermore,", circa 1930
    - Holograph notes, 1931 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - "Garner to Work With Hoover If Elected Speaker of House,", 1931 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - "Mrs. Rolph Is 'First Lady',", 1931
    - Partial manuscript on Judge Sylvain Lazarus (presiding Judge in the Roscoe "Fatty" Arbuckle case and the Liu Fook case), outline, drafts, research materials, circa 1931 (Box-folder 7: 10-13)
      This manuscript may not have been published.
    - "Prince In Tiflis," typescript of article, circa 1931 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - "Problems of U.S. Engineers in Russia", The San Francisco Daily News, 1931 September 5 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - "China and Russia Begin Negotiations as 'War' With Japan in Manchuria Ends," The Honolulu Advertiser, 1931 December 13 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - "Russia, China to Sign New Trade Treaty Which Will Be Soviet's Great Advantage," The Honolulu Advertiser, 1931 December 20
    - "Tragedies, Comedies Make Life In Moscow Quartiera Like Scenes From Balzac," The Honolulu Advertiser, 1932 January 4
    - Notes, verses, 1932 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - "Art for Nizhi Novgorod," draft, 1932 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - "American Girls in Red Russia," two page proofs of article for This EveryWeek Magazine, 1932 May 28-29 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - "Moscow's First American School," two page proofs of article for This EveryWeek Magazine, 1932 June 11-12 (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - Chapters, notes on Milly Bennett's experiences in the Soviet Union, 1933 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - "Reveals Forgotten Chaikovski Score," Moscow Daily News, 1933 April 5 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    - "'Evgeni Onegin' Resurrected," Moscow Daily News, 1933 May 5
    - "The World's Newest Drama," Moscow Daily News, 1933 June 3
    - "A Ballet Which Youth has Created," Moscow Daily News, 1933 June 8
    - "Fairy Tales in Moscow," The Honolulu Advertiser, 1933 December 2
    - "Big News Comes to Russia," The Nation, 1934 January 17 (Box-folder 8: 10)
    - "Life of Durov," partial manuscript, research materials, circa 1934 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - Carbon copy of article, probably written for the Moscow Daily News, circa 1935 (Box-folder 8: 12)
    - "Soviet Russia Discovers 'Home Sweet Home'," The New York Times Magazine, 1935 November 10 (Box-folder 8: 13)
    - "Russia's New Hero Sticks to Mines," The New York Times, 1935 December 8 (Box-folder 8: 14)
    - News cables to the International News Service from Milly Bennett, 1936 (Box-folder 8: 15)
    - Copies of news stories for the International News Service by Milly Bennett, 1936 (Box-folder 8: 16)
    - Typescripts, carbon copies, parts of articles, notes, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 9: 1-3)
    - Typescripts, carbon copies for the Associated Press, written in Spain by Milly Bennett, 1937 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Carbons, drafts, notes - Spain, 1937 (Box-folder 9: 5-7)